<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>#Game-Design on Terminal</title>
    <link>/tags/%23game-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in #Game-Design on Terminal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/%23game-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mesmer Argosi</title>
      <link>/posts/mesmer-argosi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/mesmer-argosi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blending the concepts of &lt;strong&gt;Mesmer&lt;/strong&gt; (from &lt;strong&gt;Guild Wars&lt;/strong&gt;) and &lt;strong&gt;Argosi&lt;/strong&gt; (from &lt;strong&gt;Sebastian de Castell&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Greatcoats&lt;/em&gt; series), we get a combination of &lt;strong&gt;illusion, trickery, manipulation&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;card games&lt;/strong&gt; based on strategy, luck, and social influence. Below are several &lt;strong&gt;concepts&lt;/strong&gt; that blend these two fascinating ideas:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Mesmer%20Argosi-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image Description&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-illusionary-gambit&#34;&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Illusionary Gambit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A game or technique where &lt;strong&gt;Mesmer-like&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;illusionary tactics&lt;/strong&gt; are used in &lt;strong&gt;trick-taking&lt;/strong&gt; games, manipulating the &lt;strong&gt;perception of other players&lt;/strong&gt;. Players could use cards, similar to &lt;strong&gt;Argosi&lt;/strong&gt;, but also include magical elements that cause opponents to see false hands or play tricks on their minds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-trick-of-the-mind&#34;&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Trick of the Mind&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A playstyle where players &lt;strong&gt;read and deceive&lt;/strong&gt; their opponents using &lt;strong&gt;psychological tactics&lt;/strong&gt;, akin to &lt;strong&gt;Mesmer&lt;/strong&gt; illusions and the &lt;strong&gt;Argosi&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt; art of cards. Players are given the ability to &lt;strong&gt;create false choices&lt;/strong&gt;, leading others to misplay or fall for traps while &lt;strong&gt;maintaining an air of diplomacy and poise&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-arcane-deception&#34;&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Arcane Deception&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A card game in which &lt;strong&gt;Mesmer-inspired magic&lt;/strong&gt; distorts the &lt;strong&gt;reality&lt;/strong&gt; of the &lt;strong&gt;cards in play&lt;/strong&gt;. Players can use spells to alter what the &lt;strong&gt;opponent sees&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;change outcomes&lt;/strong&gt; based on hidden strategies, just like &lt;strong&gt;Argosi cards&lt;/strong&gt; manipulating one&amp;rsquo;s future. A player could alter what &lt;strong&gt;cards&lt;/strong&gt; their opponents draw or discard.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-the-conductors-game&#34;&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;The Conductor’s Game&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Mesmeric strategy game&lt;/strong&gt; where players control an intricate &lt;strong&gt;web of illusions&lt;/strong&gt; that influence the moves of the game. Cards in the game could represent &lt;strong&gt;characters&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;situations&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;spells&lt;/strong&gt;, each one bending the rules of the game in subtle ways. Players could &lt;strong&gt;play both sides&lt;/strong&gt; while appearing neutral, weaving intricate deceptions much like an &lt;strong&gt;Argosi&lt;/strong&gt; in the &lt;strong&gt;Greatcoats&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-ethereal-shuffle&#34;&gt;5. &lt;strong&gt;Ethereal Shuffle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A game of chance where &lt;strong&gt;Mesmeric magic&lt;/strong&gt; allows players to &lt;strong&gt;switch cards&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;manipulate others&amp;rsquo; hands&lt;/strong&gt;, much like the &lt;strong&gt;Argosi&lt;/strong&gt;’s use of card play to affect outcomes. The twist: players may not even know if the magic they cast has altered the results or if they are simply &lt;strong&gt;making decisions&lt;/strong&gt; based on trickery.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-sleight-of-the-arcana&#34;&gt;6. &lt;strong&gt;Sleight of the Arcana&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A game or event in which &lt;strong&gt;Mesmer-like illusions&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;change the stakes&lt;/strong&gt; during the game, shifting the &lt;strong&gt;meaning&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;individual cards&lt;/strong&gt;. Like the &lt;strong&gt;Argosi&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo;s use of cards for communication, players would use illusions to make it unclear whether they are playing truthfully or &lt;strong&gt;influencing others&amp;rsquo; actions&lt;/strong&gt; through &lt;strong&gt;misdirection&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-the-facade-hand&#34;&gt;7. &lt;strong&gt;The Facade Hand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A trick-taking game where players use &lt;strong&gt;Mesmer&lt;/strong&gt; techniques to &lt;strong&gt;conceal&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;reveal&lt;/strong&gt; cards in their hands. Just like &lt;strong&gt;Argosi&lt;/strong&gt;, this would involve &lt;strong&gt;strategic bluffing&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;subtle manipulations&lt;/strong&gt; of what’s shown, causing confusion about the state of the game.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-vesper&#34;&gt;8. &lt;strong&gt;Vesper&amp;rsquo;s Trick&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Mesmer&lt;/strong&gt;-infused version of an &lt;strong&gt;Argosi game&lt;/strong&gt; where each round features a &lt;strong&gt;bluff&lt;/strong&gt; based on &lt;strong&gt;hidden motives&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;emotional manipulation&lt;/strong&gt;. Players can &lt;strong&gt;mimic&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;copy&lt;/strong&gt; other players&amp;rsquo; cards, twisting the rules of the game itself, only for the &lt;strong&gt;true result&lt;/strong&gt; to be revealed much later, influenced by both &lt;strong&gt;illusion&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;psychological play&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;9-mimicry-pact&#34;&gt;9. &lt;strong&gt;Mimicry Pact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;card game&lt;/strong&gt; where every &lt;strong&gt;Mesmer&lt;/strong&gt; character can &lt;strong&gt;mimic&lt;/strong&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;abilities of others&lt;/strong&gt;, but at a cost. Players engage in &lt;strong&gt;cooperative deceit&lt;/strong&gt;, learning to &lt;strong&gt;read others&amp;rsquo; intentions&lt;/strong&gt; while simultaneously &lt;strong&gt;influencing their own moves&lt;/strong&gt; by blending &lt;strong&gt;argosi-inspired card exchanges&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;mind-bending illusions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;10-illusive-decree&#34;&gt;10. &lt;strong&gt;Illusive Decree&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Mesmer-powered game of social intrigue&lt;/strong&gt; combined with &lt;strong&gt;Argosi’s trickery&lt;/strong&gt;, where players use &lt;strong&gt;illusionary decrees&lt;/strong&gt; that subtly influence others’ decisions. This game would revolve around players casting &lt;strong&gt;spells or challenges&lt;/strong&gt; that alter the rules or shape the &lt;strong&gt;cards’ meaning&lt;/strong&gt;, creating an atmosphere where no one can be sure if the &lt;strong&gt;outcome is real&lt;/strong&gt; or a &lt;strong&gt;deception&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These concepts are designed to blend the &lt;strong&gt;strategic depth&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;trick-taking card games&lt;/strong&gt; (like the &lt;strong&gt;Argosi&lt;/strong&gt;) with the &lt;strong&gt;illusory, mind-bending powers&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mesmers&lt;/strong&gt;, offering gameplay that’s about &lt;strong&gt;manipulating perceptions&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;subtle deceptions&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;mental strategy&lt;/strong&gt;. Whether it’s through magical illusions or &lt;strong&gt;bluffing mechanics&lt;/strong&gt;, these ideas invite a game experience where every player has to stay one step ahead of their opponents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
